okay here we go so we're studying
Nagarjuna his name is Arya Nagar genus
sometimes he's called just the Arya so
he's the most famous Aria in Buddhist
history okay he lived 280 we think about
1800 years ago I think
Patanjali lived at the same time the
yoga sutra author because a lot of the a
lot of the issues that Patanjali talks
about are found in the god-honest time
okay so just after the Christian era
started maybe 200 years after them and I
think there may have been some
connection with Christianity
Thomas disciple Thomas which is a
student of Jesus came to India to a
place called Taxila
and worked for a king named the Greeks
call him God the forest and LA the
Romans call him Gaspar and he was one of
the three kings who came to Bethlehem
and Thomas worked for him and that was
part of India at that time now it's part
of Afghanistan and so I think there was
some connection
Thomas ended up in South India in Madras
which is now called Chennai and he spent
many years there his churches still
there he was he was murdered there he
was killed there
all of South India now is Christian
Kerala State does those states are
Christian and the gardener comes from
those states the gardener comes from the
South bed day you is his home place and
if you go to the monastery Sarah may the
greatest monastery from the airport in
Bangalore you pastor in the gardener's
hometown that's where you buy coconut
okay so if you see coconuts just stop
and so he was from South India and great
the greatest teacher about emptiness
okay and this is his greatest book on
emptiness called wisdom he wrote I don't
know we have about 10 or 15 books by him
I'm teaching some of them in Guangzhou
two of his great letters for King's
government running government running
big companies and we're learning that in
Wang Tao walked out in Guangzhou
vidiians program if you're interested
talk to her and it's a very very cool
program called the way of kings and so
we're gonna be studying his wisdom which
is his greatest book and it became the
basis of all the later explanations of
emptiness so any country China and Japan
Korea Vietnam India Tibet any place you
study emptiness you are studying the
garden you are studying his works okay
so I just thought it would be nice I
tried to spread it out for five years so
we'll do it once
here for 10 days and we'll go through
wisdom okay there are three commentaries
that I would like to use one is by
jetsam copper and it's probably the
greatest commentary on the Guardian and
it's called the ocean of emptiness
richtig yacht so say Victor got oh yeah
that victim means proofs of emptiness
okay proofs of emptiness so I like to
call the book shortname we can call it
the ocean of emptiness so that was
written by its own copper if we
translate it it will take 15,000 25,000
sorry 2,500 pages okay it'll be a big
book if we translate some copper and
he's quite difficult and another teacher
named Tony Lama and his dates are
sixteen seventy five to seventeen forty
eight he wrote a very digestible
commentary so it's difficult but it's
not indigestion or diarrhea it's just
difficult but it's not impossible so if
you read Tony Lama first which is about
two hundred folios it would be about a
thousand pages the translation will be
about a thousand pages which is pretty
doable for our team our mixed nuts team
with we do about three four thousand
pages a year so we can we can do it if
we have time if we don't have to spend
time on fund raising other
if someone else raises the money to
finish the rugs at Diamond Mountain I
can finish Johnny llama so it's up to
you I can't do both I can't do I really
can't do both
either I raise money which I'm happy to
do because we need roads or I can
translate which nobody else can do you
understand so help me out okay don't
don't make me ask okay just do it
seven thousand dollars talk to rob Russ
injure okay we spent about four hundred
thousand already they're not finished
okay the even the new ones have holes in
them so it's a difficult job it's a big
job but this place would be so cool if
we have finished the roads if we don't
finish the roads I'm worried about the
high road it's dangerous it's very
dangerous and it's not covered yet so
the rain is making the dangerous road
smaller and smaller
I'm afraid somebody will fly down the
mountain in a car so help me out let's
figure it out let's figure it out if you
decide to do something you can do it
especially with many people many
countries we all pasted them we can do
it it's not impossible don't think I
can't do it we did this building we did
the other building that was 2 million
dollars that's nothing it was 700
nothing ok we can do it ok but we all
have to try ok
so you kind of need a ship to go on the
ocean of some couple Oh Oh some couples
book is difficult so you kind of need a
boat to go on that ocean of emptiness so
he so copies book is called ocean of
emptiness and then Tony Lama wrote a
book called a ship that you can use on
the ocean of emptiness and it's a joke
he's talking about some couples book he
said I will be your ship captain I have
a nice boat
just getting my boat we can cross this
soak up no problem okay so we're gonna
finish Tony Lamas commentary he also
wrote a second commentary called Connie
difficult points in in wisdom and we'll
be using that also the greatest
commentary of all time on the gardener
is chandrakirti about 650 he wrote a
book called what entering the middle way
okay if you're gonna translate it you
better know the title he wrote two
commentaries one is called entering the
middle way Medea maka Avatar and the
other book is called persona father
which means clear clarifying the words
he the persona pas de commentary
explains the words of wisdom this book
you're studying and then entering the
middle way explains the meaning and
those books are the basis of all
emptiness teachings in Archon you know
in the countries you come from Vietnam
China Korea
the books came to during the Tong Xiao
Tong dynasty came to Xian translated by
the other mixed nuts team spent on his
student was the answer
whose real name is when Chuck he's from
Korea and he went home and he spread it
there and then the Japanese took the
Tong dynasty teachings directly into
Japan and they kept them very strong
they are still there
so this is how this book came what's the
name of the godless book just call
wisdom okay people have these long names
forget it okay
what's the Sanskrit pres Nia say
prisoner so the Russians are correct
pronunciation yes no it's a torture
watching at least me okay the Russian
pronunciation of these words is very
pure okay closer to Sanskrit is near
means to know pres Nia means super
knowledge wisdom The Guardian is book is
called just called wisdom okay and
that's what we're studying okay
so if the first homework question says
what is the ship on the sea of emptiness
you're gonna say or the sea of emptiness
is some couples commentary and then we
need a ship on that sea and that's John
enormous commentary and we are riding in
that ship okay and we'll be giving you
an old book every day will be getting
you more stuff to put in the notebook
there's a long 55 pages on the lions
dance
okay we keep improving it we keep
updating
and it's based on my trails teaching
okay called the jewel of realizations
are be some melancholy anything
innovating engine on young shooting a
tangent of Newton limits in the top edge
a very famous lines singer vision better
with that lion stance
okay singers like Singapore Singapore
comes from that and lion city of lions
right right you Singaporeans are Lions
okay alright so anyway that's just an
antenna so that's how we're gonna be
studying all right ship on the sea of
antennas so I called the second course
to ship just to remind you okay how many
courses we're gonna have on the gardener
fine okay try to come to all of them
it's very frustrating for me the one I
have to repeat or I have to remind you
know it's difficult for me to teach
fifty fifty people who came and didn't
come then I have to waste time repeating
things okay
all right deal alright so if you don't
build the roads you're gonna fall off
the roof in three years from now okay we
studied two chapters already the four in
the first course last year at this time
we studied the first two chapters how
many chapters total in wisdom 27 okay
very famous 27 chapters okay and we
studied the names of the chapters we
studied how the structure of the
chapters and how did the gardener choose
to teach emptiness his nickname is the
aria the Arya like New York people
called New York the city Mexico people
Mexico City people come Mexico City
Mexico it's like
Guangzhou people called Guangzhou China
[Laughter]
so that are the big idea is Nakata okay
so we just sometimes we call him just
the Aria okay
New Mexico sleepy I know they I stay
where you from Mexico
yeah we're City okay so we finished two
chapters the first chapter was oh by the
way I had a cool new idea yesterday day
before I want you to learn some Sanskrit
well we are learning wisdom okay so you
should learn some important words so
every homework I'm gonna give you three
Sanskrit words that way you will learn
30 or 40 sounds good words and that's
almost enough to speak Pasha
when you get to sort of buyer rights
against Indonesian language is very very
tightly based on Sanskrit so we're gonna
learn some Sanskrit words while we go
okay you should know some some words
okay so we're gonna learn three Sanskrit
words every class okay stay pariksha
pariksha okay and I'm gonna tell you
there's two things on your homework okay
number one
by the way I put the words on your
homework and it has the meaning of the
word and it has the roots of the word
that came into English okay that's
called cognate okay cognate means the
word came from Sanskrit almost directly
into English so it's useful to know the
cognates okay
what's the cognate for prisoners near
sneer
what's the cognate in English yeah I
know I know okay
that's why English has that irritating
okay okay it should be Canal so the
reason English has a K and I know it
comes from this yeah okay it's the J
came from Sanskrit came into K that's
why this strange spelling in English I
know I know okay in W that's des Nia
okay so if you know these cognates you
can remember the Sanskrit okay I told
you yesterday what's important about
Sanskrit all Buddhists speak Sanskrit
all Buddhists speak sense me okay
all Buddhists speak sense when you
become a Buddha you're gonna have to
speak Sanskrit you might as well start
now then secondly you can impress your
friends if you add a cocktail party and
you want to impress somebody I can tell
you about that okay non-alcoholic
cocktails right okay so we finished the
first each chapter is called parrisha
separation correction
so that's on your homework actually I
gave it to you on your homework one of
the three Sanskrit words will be on your
quiz okay one of the three Sanskrit
words I gave you for free on your
homework I put it on your homework with
the explanation the meaning and cognates
okay and then you just have to memorize
those three and one of them is gonna be
on your quiz if you want to know which
one pay me $10 okay maybe parrisha okay
correction means to examine a question
analyze a question I I like the word
investigation investigation okay each
chapter of wisdom is an investigation we
are checking something we are checking
some question okay and that's the
structure which is a homework question
that's the structure of wisdom okay it's
a prediction each chapter is called
prediction investigation we are checking
like police investigation who killed
this guy okay then the structure of
wisdom each chapter is apparition okay
prediction means investigate so the
structure of each chapter is the same
the first thing okay this is on your
homework the first thing someone will
come with a stupid idea okay someone
will come with a stupid idea like my
husband is yelling at me in the kitchen
because he's tired and he didn't eat yet
and there was a bad traffic okay that's
according to Buddhism super products too
Plus stupid okay idea oh why your
husband is yelling at you tonight
oh he's tired and I didn't fix dinner
yet and he had a lot of traffic okay
like that okay so if you're gonna write
a chapter called if you're gonna write
the 28th chapter of wisdom you can call
it the husband in the kitchen okay and
the first sentences will be somebody
will come and give a stupid idea it's
always a structure okay oh why your
husband yell at you oh he's tired and he
didn't have dinner yet
and his boss yelled at him and he had
bad traffic okay so somebody will come
and make a stupid idea
okay then the gardener will fight it
okay the guys no fighting okay he's
style and I want to see that on your
homework okay his style is simplicity
and elegance okay his style is
simplicity elegance and practical he
always uses short words short poetry and
he uses the ideas of the normal world
okay he uses the ideas of the normal
world like on your homework the last
assignment on each homework is called
real application say real up it means to
read not rap okay real application okay
and the gardener was very very good
he was the greatest philosopher of
ancient India and what made him great
was he took it to the kitchen okay he
always takes it to the kitchen
he doesn't just blahblah philosophy okay
he always takes it to the kitchen so
homework assignment each day is a real
application you make up a real
application if you're not sure how to do
it talk to hustle where are you
he could teach you party pills right and
maybe Tim will organize a little
competition for the best okay
how did real lab happen you see a CI is
the guessing course the ACI course is
that you're learning in the evening
these are the Geshe course okay then
people started inviting me to teach
business courses or relationship courses
or how not to fire on your husband
courses and I have to use the Gashi
course to find out how to use it in
business how to use it in the kitchen
okay then DCI is the real app of a Siri
okay DCI comes from a CI DCI is the
gadget course made for fighting families
and people who want to have a business
okay so why I get paid so much money to
give away the money it's because I know
how to make a real app that's all I know
how to take easy a CI and make it into
DCI and then I booked two three years
from now every day's book okay and
people throwing money so I want to teach
you okay you take the ACI and you make
the DCI and that's called real app and
the best example is in Shenzhen China
coolest city in the world right now I
think
and they have this China software
program my kids and when I went there it
was very similar to today so I have to
go there directly from time on to teach
the China's soft power these are
business executives right mr. moose one
of them we have some China South Park
guys here welcome thank you for coming
and just like now the first time we had
turned soft are I'm not ready to teach
I'm too busy I have to do Diamond
Mountain I have the DCI manual I had 860
page manual for teacher teacher training
my head exploding my last hair is
falling out John Barry knows two things
happen when you get work number one the
hair falls out then some of it comes to
your ears I don't know why
so anyway I'm stressed out I'm not ready
for Chinese supper so I think what to do
you know I have idea I told Stanley
hours we will make the student to write
the course and that would be the course
so we told them you have to take the
material and you have to make the real
app so they come to the young sense
translation we are translating one of
the greatest books of all time from Tong
dynasty it will be I think eight
thousand pages to translation so they
come to the translation class and then
they have to make their own applications
okay and that's the whole idea right you
invent the next husband in the kitchen
okay you invent the next husband in the
kitchen all right it's an exercise for
you the first ones you do after five
years you can look back they are totally
stupid okay and wrong okay
that's okay you learned how okay you
learn how and one hustle made a great
one that's a great one
that's so cool so talk to him if you're
not sure so each homework you need to
take these emptiness ideas and you have
to make a real em okay how do you use it
in the real life okay
people gonna ask you why you went to
Arizona you said oh I I learned two
thousand-year-old business strategies
you know I'm gonna be rich
I'm not just sitting in the desert okay
okay so who did that before the guy's
name is the gardener and he made relapse
and his style let the guy come and make
a stupid idea
each Perisher what's aperture each
investigation each chapter stupid guy
comes the guards that base him with
normal relapse okay with illness and
then Charlie Lama comes and he says this
wasn't made up by the gardener this
comes from the ancient Buddhist talk and
he identifies each Sutra for each
partition okay so three things going on
in each chapter this is on your homework
number one somebody comes and says
something stupid like my husband was
tired that's where he's joining why is
the husband really yelling because you
yelled at your kids last week that's the
gardener comes and says that that's his
real out first there's a real stupid
then there's a real up
okay then we get the real scripture
Choni mama steps in and says by the way
don't think the Guardian had made up
this real he's this comes directly from
the heart center
so Tony lama in the structure
Tony Lama will step in third he will say
oh look this comes from the real screw
this comes from the Buddha okay the
gaijin is just quoting the Buddha
alright okay so we finished the first
two chapters the first chapter was
called examination of conditions factors
factors okay how does one thing make
another thing happen we finished that
that was the first chapter okay then the
second chapter for $10 yes the gang mr.
greedy yeah coming and going okay coming
and going shopping $10 for the gentleman
from Surabaya
I mean Singapore and his wife okay so
yeah the second chapter how do you come
how do you go what happens when you come
what happens when you go when I walk
through the door what's really happening
what is really happening pictures coming
out of my mind
small door bigger door bigger door
bigger door big big then I get to the
door smaller door its minor its mother's
manner
I don't walk I don't go through the door
okay picture picture did we call it
working it doesn't work through the door
there's never worked through any door
picture small door it's a big door small
we call it walking with Naggar Janice
say it's not real question when the
gardeners say it's not real never he
will never say that
that's real walking through the door
well what's my old walk isn't door
that's not real the way you always
thought how you got it how did you get
to Diamond Mountain tell me how you got
to Diamond okay give me in the garden
answer how did you get to Diamond you
gave rides to other people in the Paris
that's all that's all you didn't come
here in a car you didn't come here in a
highway you didn't fly the airplane
forget that you helped other people to
go somewhere the gardener says that's
real that's real did this flying in a
plane that's not real that's not what
happening that's like the husband who's
mad because he didn't eat okay it's not
real okay got it
so that's the second chapter now who run
the third chapter we're gonna study six
chapters okay this time we're gonna
study six chapters three of them are
short okay chapter three chapter four
chapter five are short well how many did
I say
yeah we're gonna study six chapters
three four five six seven eight okay so
on your homework the longest question
which is done on your quiz don't even
study it it's too long for a quiz give
me the names of those parishes okay
chapters names okay by the way the
pieces of prediction is say party each
party
each party means all around now listen
when you want to find an English cognate
in English any an easy way is to change
all the A's to e
generally speaking the a in Sanskrit
will often change to e in English so
what's party become pari like periscope
or perimeter or perihelion I don't know
pari means all around like periscope on
a submarine means you can see all around
perimeter means the border around the
place okay so peri means all around
akia means to look okay HM means to look
okay and that came into German which is
the root of English as
algún alga and then that became ocular
and words for I words for the eye okay
ocular up optometrist optometry okay
these are words okay
many English I words come from e-i comes
from alchemy in white okay so I comes
from Asia so party action means check it
out okay examine investigate okay
investigate what who's being
investigated for $20 who's not you what
a word gave you the initiation for $20
who's being investigated in this book
who's been investigating to see who he's
the investigator horn who's being
investigated
Chintan emptiness no chicken last chance
ten nine eight seven six five four three
two he's the investigate tour okay now
the money is canceled
we could spend all day he's
investigating these other stupid guys
okay oh my husband is upset he yell at
me all the time
why oh maybe he's hungry or he's tired
we had a bad day let's investigate that
we're gonna investigate what you said
okay got it
it's the first guy who comes in each
chapter is being investigated why you
say such a stupid thing
let's check okay let's check let's check
why you are wrong okay so each chapter
is called a prediction buddy yeah okay
by the way when I miss I it gets long I
but I didn't put it on your homework
I've made it simple for you okay it's
really party because it's party each
other the two he means it and it gets
longer party okay it means I'm gonna
check I'm gonna investigate let's
investigate okay all right okay now
chapter 3 investigation of the powers
sense powers okay I ear nose tongue
Heart Sutra right subway come home boy
such a shame she felluci we're gonna
check each eye ear nose tongue body and
mind and always we go down the body
Heart Sutra goes down the body eyes eyes
yes nose mouth body mine okay we're
gonna investigate the sense powers okay
and I put it on your stands with
homework say indriya indriya it means
power sends power your eyes your ears
you know okay so you only have three
sanskrit words okay don't explode your
head okay
say india okay and that means in in in
ancient asian books indra means power
and there's a god hindu god named indra
it means very powerful person okay the
English word I win I win the game I win
the football match it comes from Indra
okay so there are means doer
okay so Indra means super-powerful it
means your eyes powerful your ears are
powerful your nose is puff your tongue
has the power and this we go to sue
gongs text has a deep relationship to
these chapters v link of the Wheel of
Life kitchen not a kitchen your sense
powers your equipment to experience the
world okay without this equipment you
cannot touch things and you cannot do
anything
okay so we're gonna check out where did
these powers come from India okay where
did this what's the cognate when I win
the game tar or indra the hindu god okay
powerful god okay indra so we're gonna
investigate the powers why two reasons
okay - is this is on your homework
everything's on your homework
why do you have four lunches on your
home just kidding
first of all
the Buddha taught for 51 years or
something we have 990 books by Lord
Buddha in in our scriptures he gave
hundreds and hundreds of lectures okay
those lectures are divided into three
turnings of the wheel three periods of
his life okay the first period of his
life teaching is called the boring
period okay there's five heaps there's
twelve ayudarnos there's 18 categories
there's a Four Noble Truths it's like a
bunch of lists he's like an accountant
it's the accountant kid okay
just making long lists and all the guys
in the first period of the Buddhist
teaching were nerds they're all like
watch number 17 I don't know you know
that's called I my family's not here
right you give the direct translation to
the Nerds so that was the first teacher
in the world
okay then in the second period of his
life Buddha said oh people are just
making lists let's teach them reality
which is emptiness okay Jing Jing Jing
contain heart sutra diamond color Sutra
these come from the second period of his
teaching okay what happened in the third
period the Nerds met emptiness guys and
they had a disagreement so Buddha said
after his second period he said how do
you like what I taught and the nurse
said it's very good it's all list we
like him then the emptiness guy said no
no he just taught emptiness for 10 more
years
everything's empty forget the list you
know then they had a big fight then they
came to just like DCI people they said
people let's go ask - you know let's
make an appointment with - you know he
will tell us which one is chlorine then
just like just to be the referee yes the
Buddha made list yes everything is empty
they go together okay that's called the
third turning of the wheel and the mind
only school came out of it okay
Buddha said they go together come on
cooperate with each other don't make me
referee between you guys okay what am I
talking about that chapter three chapter
four chapter five are for the Nerds
chapter three chapter four chapter five
for the nurse there for the guys who
like the old lists by Buddha only five
heaps twelve doors of sense 18
categories for higher truth four ways of
taking birth twelve links of dependent
nation okay
so chapter three chapter four chapter
five those nerds Dobby diamond nerds who
took control of Buddhism for 700 years
okay they took control of Buddhism the
Nerds were the big Buddhist for seven
hundred years after the Buddha died okay
I don't know what happened the emptiness
guys were probably meditating
then the Nerds to cover for 700 years
okay and everybody loved abhidharma 4/7
they're just making Buddhism became nerd
religion okay and they translate into
Pali and a lot of nerdy stuff okay it's
frankly it's a little dry I'll be
Dharma's very it's drier than diamond I
translate it for 12 years
okay I memorized okay a second dimension
and see like that
so I respect it but it's boring okay so
the first chapter 3 chapter 4 chapter 5
the Nerds are coming and we have to do
what to them pariksha we have to
investigate them they're gonna come and
say stupid things and then we're gonna
interesting it's like police
investigation what do you think oh
here's chapter 3 okay but I thought the
sense powers how many five six depends
on how you count them well then how do
you know you have sensible oh you got
contact between one in the case of the
eye contact between one
yeah blue collar the eyeball that
detects the blue color and then the mind
which is aware of the eyeball and the
color okay these are called the powers
in Buddhism this is called the powers
sometimes divided into twelve six six
senses six objects visible things here
about things malleable things terrible
things feelable things think about
things okay and then the six of them
this is one of the fundamental teachings
of the first turning of the wheel is
called the powers or the powers of doors
of sense okay in three okay now what do
you think the nerd comes in says okay
for $100 what do you think he says what
do you think he says $100 ten nine seven
raise your hand
six five it doesn't cost anything to
guess four
okay what okay what was my question why
do you think what's the stupid thing
that the nerd comes in the beginning of
chapter three and he says yeah they are
saying that those are coming from itself
so it is your eye are you looking at me
in the gardener can you see don't give
me this crap about Denise
Buddha taught the powers it's in the
coat check the first turning in the
wheel I'm not saying anything this
stupid stuff about emptiness in the
garden what do you mean the eyes not
real okay poke out your eye and see what
happens
you still gonna see stuff you know so
there they're like absurd the guy comes
to come on the is really sees things you
need eye the eye works the eye works
okay don't tell me something don't tell
me it's not real what are you talking
about how are you using your eyeball oh
but it's not real yeah everything's
empty you know so you can't see me right
like they're very irritated with the
gardener okay you second returning a
real dude why did Buddha spend so much
time during the first turn the wheel to
teach the six senses and this is how we
communicate with the world
they're not super real
you can't even listen to my stupid
statements except you have to use your
ears which have their own power if they
don't have to why do you call them power
they have their own power okay got it
this is how you communicate with the
world that's chapter 3 okay we're gonna
talk more about it each class we will do
one chapter I designed the classes to
spread over the chapters so you're gonna
get like a lot of chapter 3 and then you
get a taste of chapter 4 and then you go
home and meditate so I want you to feel
the bridges between the chapters okay so
each assignment each class is gonna be
kind of mainly one chapter and then a
taste of the next chapter to get your
mind ready for the next day
okay alright chapter four let's
investigate
parts of a person let's investigate the
parts of a person okay five heaps okay
five heaps nowadays I just say body and
mind okay in English its body and mind
okay in Buddhism we say five heaps it's
the same thing it's the same thing okay
you can call it body in mind you can
call it the five heaps why are they
called the five the five parts of a
person I called the five heaps why for
$20 this is a cheap question pulling
down k go Ricky the pump okay to
Colombian first chapter why are they
called well either part why didn't go to
say parts of a person because that's all
they are they justify parts and hustle
they are called hips because you have to
put them all together to work good gasp
it's a ten dollar gas your clothes your
clothes
come on answer it today we have to keep
going I was waiting for the microphone
some of them are not physical there's
the emotional okay okay listen it's very
simple
I'll be Thomas a spunky gonna get in
trouble can't you come Dominion we call
them heaps because they're piles of lots
of each one has lots of stuff piled
that's why they're so just think of them
as groups okay a person is made of five
groups of things your body your feelings
your discriminations your mind why did I
do this your mind and everything else
okay number four is called everything
else do Jimbo solution definition oh you
got your body many parts you got your
feelings many kinds of feelings you
discriminate between things this is good
this is bad this is many kinds of
discriminations you have many kinds of
awareness okay look it's not the bad
finger it's the third finger okay and
you got everything else okay this is
everything else got it doesn't so
chapter 4 we're gonna investigate the
five parts to a person now we're
especially gonna investigate the first
heap okay the whole chapter four is
about the first team what is the first
team yeah your body because the guy
comes mr. stupid head first turning
wheel guy in the first three chapters
it's mainly first turn these accountants
the accountant comes to know five heaps
mean what's the first team physical body
physical body you telling me empty I'm
real you want me to punch you with my
unreal hand you okay the guardsmen can I
punch you it's not real it's all
emptiness okay they're like come on this
is super real you know
you feed it every day the guys in there
don't tell me it's emptiness got it
that's chapter four we are partitioning
the parts of the parts of the person but
we focus on the body the first one okay
chapter what's the next chapter fine
that's according to Buddhism and
according to quantum physics the
physical body is made of energies
different energies okay gravitational
electric close force weak force charm
electrons neutrons protons
quarks and other delightful things okay
chemicals elements so molecules so
science and Buddhism they both say
there's elements chemicals in the body
elemental forces gravitation electrical
force momentum these discs create the
physical body okay so good at taught
those elements okay
sometimes he called the eighteen and
sometimes he called it 5 sot - mae nam
can stay sir -
may
earth water fire wind and space okay
these are called the five elements in
Buddhism don't think they are some kind
of stupid before people knew about cell
phones don't think that these are
gravitational force weak force strong
for responding elect they are very
sophisticated extremely sophisticated
don't think the ancient Buddhists were
stupid okay they they have 60 levels of
electrons sixty the sizes are written in
the third chapter that I'll become a
second part okay you know light-years
don't think they're stupid the five
elements are not some kind of medieval
science thing you know where you bleed
people or you burn them okay it's not
that they're very sophisticated about
energy sources of the body okay so they
go from the body to the elements the
chemicals in the body how do they work
how do they work now what's the sexiest
of the five are given to you again earth
fire such earth water fire such wind and
which is sexiest one gotta be space so
in the garden of focuses on the last one
that's more sixty okay five heaps let's
talk about the first one physical in the
last chapter now this chapter five
chemicals that make your body forces
let's talk about the last one because
it's most interesting space what is
space okay but what does it mean to say
space is empty okay
alright chapter 1 chapter we on five or
six good six okay three was about the
powers for was about the heaps five is
about the elements now we reached
Chapter six
okay we are going to investigate desire
and attachment we are going to
investigate desire and attachment that
accountants are halfway out the door
okay The Guardian have by the way
chapter three chapter four chapter five
are short because I think the gardener's
Board of accounts they're sure he says
stupid stupid and stupid now can we get
to something more interesting like
desire that keeps you in this world okay
that created your body and the elements
let's talk about desire okay let's talk
about the emptiness a desire and
attachment okay
I'll give you a clue okay when I first
heard the chapter name I thought oh he's
gonna talk about you know first you get
first geshe-la
I was there when Carly had his first
donor
do you remember I think it was his first
donut so being an atoll nation's son
Kairi doesn't get to eat anything
interesting it's all green drinks you
know we were in Xalapa and you know the
waiter brought a bunch of doughnuts and
churros and I said Gary here try this
it's not green and kaiser and that's
desire okay then a second one came and
he said I said look just like me and
then became what attachment you say
first desire like he never tasted I
don't think his parents are again it
took uncle mine to give him a journal
and then he's like hmm and then now he
started to cry because he can't get the
other ones okay that's desire and
attachment
okay but it's not okay that's not the
chapter it's not about that it smells
like that but it's it's wrong okay
and I'll teach you the correct one later
okay
he's gonna investigate right pas
pariksha what is desire and what is
attachment so remind me to tell you when
we get there okay chapter 7 very long
very long it's the second longest
chapter the only longer chapter comes
later it's the four truths okay that's
the longest chapter not by much but this
chapter is the super chapter chapter
seven lesson
the game how things start how things
stay and how things stop let's
investigate how things start how things
stay and how things stop and in the
abhidharma they never teach it that
order in that order for $300 guess how
they teach in the abbey diamond and tell
me why and you don't get partial credit
10987 wait 641 okay cancel the bed in
the RV diamond they always teach you
starting stopping and staying
they never say starting staying and
stopping they always say starting
stopping and they'd good like they
listen starting stopping why why Buddha
taught it this way he doesn't want you
attached to this thing
you were born you're gonna die forget
the 70 years this this thing is like
done forget that let's focus on why you
were born and how you're gonna die
starting stopping and think cuz thing is
too short staying so sure it's not worth
talking about okay got it
cool okay chapter 7 by the way chapter 7
is going to talk a lot about
the starting of starting and this thing
of starting in the stopping of stunning
which is a abhidharma idea okay
the accountants got in there somehow no
it's not just starting staying stuffing
starting also has its own starting and
staying and stuffing in fact it starting
doesn't have a starting how can starting
start because what would start starting
okay they want the front end of the
starting that's gonna start starting to
stay for a while then they want to talk
about how to starting stop before this
thing starts Gannon okay this is a very
I'll be Dumber thing then they they
people ask them well this is starting at
the starting at this time of course does
the starting at the starting and the
starting of the starting and stopping
starting no don't ask me they just got
tired after a while some the gardens
that come where's the starting of the
study this time you know okay got it
alright chapter 8 we are gonna
investigate who does things and what did
they do who does things and what do they
do
agents and actions who does things and
what do they do
okay if things are empty how can people
do things okay if things are empty you
know how can you eat breakfast which is
my main focus I try to look beyond the
yoga class to the important things
right okay we did it in 2008
yeah me and Brian okay short yoga class
followed by a long lunch guilt-free
lunch
okay so how do we start things and we're
gonna specially talk about making pods
how does a Potter make a pun how does a
Potter make a pun because until they
make the putt you can't call them Potter
so you got to change the sentence right
how does that make the pot Potter Harry
you can't say that Potter made a podcast
the pot is not a pot until the Pradas
main so you gotta say made pot connor
like it doesn't make sense okay
something's by the way in the study of
emptiness in the garden of specialty
okay
his specialty when he starts his
prediction he says something's messed up
something's wrong with that picture
okay that's his style okay somebody
comes and says my husband's upset he
yelled at me because he was tired and
hungry in the garden goes bugging me
about that something doesn't seem right
about that
okay that's his style okay when you say
that I don't know when you say the cook
made the meal the garden is like I just
bugs me
it's just bugs me you know you can't say
that cook made the meal the cooks never
cook till they make a meal cuz cooks
make meals so until you have a meal you
can't call the guy cooks how can you
have a sentence
it starts with cook before you hit the
word meal because the cook is not a cook
unless there's a meal it's just punch me
okay
that's the gardener's style there is
every party sure he's tactically like
you we say something he goes it just
bugs me you know okay
the whole world is strange to me
everything seems wrong discuss something
else is going on
you know you feed your husband you get
him enough sleep there's no traffic and
he's still yelling you just bump me
something else is going on this and the
Gardiners things he should make a rap
song it's coming on it's not the traffic
on me
that's the guys in this town okay this
thing about people who do things okay
guys that's the the roots of furniture
first you have to bug you then you have
to check what what is really going on
and you come up with yelling at the kids
you come up with yelling at the kids
okay got him that's his style
all right you just finished an
introduction to the six chapters that
we're gonna study this ten days okay
we're gonna get through those six
chapters Oh Moneypenny
okay in the monastery O'Malley pay me
who means inshallah yeah I hope so
I'm gonna make it alright what common
theme ties together the first three of
the six chapters these are all subjects
that were taught early by the Buddha
they are fundamental to Buddhism okay we
have 18 books we are translating in the
translator classes we had sixty classes
in a row in Sedona in 10 days 10 days 12
days so many of the books that were
translating so gangs also I think we
have to go to Stanley's boring book for
information for fundamental information
okay so everybody's book everybody
complains about Stanley's book everybody
wants to translate sages book because
it's sexy and it has Tantra in it the
only book that has standards and then
everybody's bored of the accountants
book Stanley Bundy Vasu Vasu
Stanley Bundy but we all have to go to
his book many of the translators are
stealing pieces out of his book for
their book because it's fundamental this
is fundamental Buddhism the accountants
were right okay you need them okay
these fundamental Buddhism you have to
know the five heaps you have to know
that 18 categories you have to know that
12 towards a sense you must know the
twelve links of dependent origination
you must know the the four truths these
are just fundamental Buddhism okay so
that why is a significant these three
chapters three four and five right
fundamental Buddhism
what happened after 700 years of
takeover by the accountants I'll be
Dharma 700 year account what happened
the Guardian it happened again that's
you gotta feel this okay what happened
to those accounts who kicked out the
accountants from Buddhism yeah guys he
said let's take it back to something
sexy let's get something really so after
700 years he came and he changed but
isn't completely the Buddhism you know
is is not what went on for several
hundred years
just monks the in the boring month okay
just monks repeating lists you know and
after after that time pink came to God
you know okay he's called Shing their
soldiers so-called say Shing day so Jay
the inventor of the wheel
you know mr. Steve Jobs of Buddhism okay
he should get out this dude this dude by
the way he didn't say let's do the new
way he said let's get back to the real
Buddhism let's get back to a Buddha
really running which is emptiness
emptiness and emptiness and bodhichitta
love okay you you accountants are you
aware that the world is on fire
are you aware that every person is gonna
fall apart and die are you aware that
there's hundreds and thousands of people
dying every day in wars
hunger what are you making this you know
do something that will help people
creature pain
you know the guys that woke him up he
said stop this accounting you know let's
get back to love let's get back to
though they're not bug off if you give
you will get rich
what's next one she like so come she nod
if you follow your morality you will
always be happy shot if you're patient
you'll be beautiful if you have fun in
your work you will be a leader if you
meditate your mind will be peaceful if
you learn wisdom you will be liberated
but say we're doing love
accomplishes them all just focus on love
okay who said that that's the gardener
okay so it's significant that he's
teaching the first three he breaks out
he breaks out after the first few
chapters okay you are witnessing the
break out from the accounts okay
in this course you are witnessing the
change in Buddhism from Hanoi Allah to
my Hannah
okay the greater way love compassion
care about people okay you are unused
emptiness to save people use emptiness
to save people in this book in these
chapters you are witnessing the break-up
okay he suddenly switches between
chapters five and six I guess he's
breaking out okay God you gotta be aware
okay it's a whole new kind of music okay
loaf I I stick it don't know fine but
I'm not sure how it's gonna work out I'm
gonna try
okay and by the way Nick's text Nick and
they can't come here cuz a mooncake I
told him his daughter was born during
the mooncake festival he/she should be
called mooncake but his wife was playing
I don't know she I mean she said
unofficial moon King okay official
anomaly and she's very beautiful
Veronica me went to see her on the day
she was born and she has all her fingers
everything and she's super beautiful
okay we were thinking Nick's jeans
didn't get into there okay she's super
beautiful okay anyway must be all mom
anyway Nick's text now I'm in trouble
next text is it's negara using the
Hinayana to teach emptiness to the
Hinnom the next text 60 versus is
mccartney using the citrus of the
Hinayana to teach the Hinayana emptiness
okay it's very chill chill sick thank
you okay alright how much time I got
seven minutes I can do it I can do
[Music]
okay all of the classes that we'll be
doing in the second session relate to no
self-nature
okay no self-nature aspirants don't have
anything inside of Aspen's that can take
away your headache nothing okay
aspirants don't have anything inside of
aspirants that can take away your
headache nothing that's just like
thinking the husband is upset because he
didn't get dinner okay it's the same
mistake okay there's nothing inside an
aspirin that can take away your headache
what's the proof of that it doesn't work
all the time okay
don't get on a plane if it doesn't work
half the time you're gonna fall down and
die okay don't get on a plane that
doesn't work all the time don't keep
taking aspirin when it doesn't work half
the time try to figure out how how'd it
get into it okay got it
all right so this is called emptiness
okay no self-nature here's your third
Sanskrit word you ready admin admin ATM
admin ok very famous soft nature okay
what's the artment of an aspirin what
describe to me an Earthman brand aspirin
it has a chemical inside of it they're
worse they call active ingredient that's
admin admin means something inside that
makes the thing work okay self-nature
self-nature
aspen has something inside that makes it
work okay that fake thing that doesn't
work is called admin in in in sanskrit
in buddhist central in buddhist center
now for hindu people admin can be a word
for god okay so don't go up to your
Indian friends and say there's no
Hartmann administered aspirin so just
respect the word admin in their religion
means God okay
now when we say admin we mean the thing
inside the aspirin that makes it work
right which don't exist there's no
chemical inside an aspirin that makes it
work now you're gonna have to give me
the roots of the word Othman say ah
cumin cumin I means not in Sanskrit it's
a long a this time I don't ask me why I
mean it's not okay we have it in English
he's an atheist means he doesn't believe
in God the whole population of the
United States is apathetic about
criminal actions by certain people I
apathetic means not interested not not
passionate uh atheist means okay not
religious okay so it's a it came into
Greek initial a it means not okay then
Taman tongue Tamar means to split or to
divide okay so what an atom that thing
which cannot cannot be Tama come on you
cannot split it then that become Adam
Adam okay so at man is related to Adam
okay the word temple we're in a temple
right now comes from the same root term
because in the old times the temple had
to be separated from the village so if
they don't put it in the middle of the
village because the village is dirty the
temple should be separate Tama from the
village so we call temple
okay separated place temp place okay so
that's on your one of them is on your
quiz okay Adam indriya in but each okay
Venetia okay good
how much time I got two minutes
oh my god we might have to cut the
iographer short who's teaching who's
teaching the medium class
ooh I'll forget that I'll keep going
he's gonna make us do splits right where
are you just admit it you gonna make us
displacement boys can't do splits I
understand we have the first certified
heap now emptiness divided into two
parts emptiness of people in the
emptiness of things and it's a big theme
in this two kinds of emptiness people
and things for $50.00
where's the to emptiness in the kitchen
for $50 where's the to emptiness in the
kitchen you ready okay try you can't
lose anything okay no problem of people
it's the wife and the husband the wife
the husband and the ring is like the
yelling or the criticizing 60 60 I fear
he gave a $60 question to a $30 anything
that's what I like perfectly and don't
get me here
in his in Israel period means
responsible so anyway
okay perfect answer in the kitchen the
emptiness of the person is that I didn't
do anything husband okay that's no don't
exist okay that emptiness is a person
now but geshe-la
there's there's proof that he's angry
red-faced loud noise you know this thing
you know it's definitely proof his face
color the sound of his voice the
wrinkles and these are all real okay so
sometimes we can say okay this husband
husband I admit he's not real but look
gasma
the red face the noise the wrinkles
those are real the parts are real the
guy's not real I understand I didn't do
any husband don't exist
come on who made his face man I didn't
make his face friend he made his face
red he made his face wrinkled he made
the noise the gardener say I'm gonna
polish it that smells wrong something's
wrong something's wrong about that okay
by the way that's called the emptiness
of things red face loud noise okay
wrinkles those are called emptiness of
things where did the red face come from
specifically in this case in the kitchen
for zero dollars
who made the red face how you had a red
face when you yelled at your kids check
it out okay you had a red face in your
kids
the pieces were made by you and the hole
was made right by you
the hole is the husband the pieces are
red face bowed noise okay got it now you
know the connection the whole structure
of wisdom is around those two kinds of
emptiness people and things and by which
one we're gonna be in this whole session
this whole course we're gonna be in the
emptiness if you want to guess for zero
dollars
see anyway you got a 50% chance yeah
the parts of your body the sense powers
you know
okay got it alright mainly okay last
question not finished in discussing the
eyeball okay we're gonna go to the first
chapter third chapter right the first of
our chapters in discussing the eye so
each time he goes to a prediction he
takes the most important thing like when
he teaches the five hips he takes your
body when he teaches
[Music]
five elements he focuses on space sexy
something sexy and when it takes the
powers the abhidharma says 90% of human
experience is visual 90% of human
experience is visual okay you you most
often judge people not by how they smell
unless it's really strong look okay you
judge everything with your eyes okay now
if the eye is seeing things
self-existent ly from its own side then
it should always see everything if the
eye sees is the aspen heels it should
heal all the time okay when an aspen
doesn't work sometimes there's somebody
in the background saying that bugs me
you know he's got the active ingredient
it really has that you mean it doesn't
work something bugs me about that okay
now in the garden is like if an aspirin
is has an augment if an aspirin has
something inside of it that takes away
your headache you should work every time
if your eye has something inside it that
sees it should see all the time and it
should see $100 nine eight
7:42 won the I should see the I if the
AI has admin if the eye has seen inside
of it then when you look at the
beautiful sky a diamond you should also
see your eyeball okay and if there's
something you don't see with your eye
then the eye is nothing okay it's like a
speck got it
you okay if Aspen doesn't work forty
percent of time thirty percent time it
then it doesn't work what the way you
think and if the eye if there's
something the eye cannot see that's
right next to the eye then the eyes not
working the way your thing okay the eye
isn't seeing things get used to it
okay your eyes not doing anything okay
you helped blind people my mom I'm so
proud of her she's 92 she's losing her
eye sight macular degeneration right so
I said what are you doing about it she
says I'm signed up to help blind people
I'm working once a week she spends one
day a week at the blind teaching them to
read with their fingers I said mom
you're so cool and her eyes getting much
better okay so understand why does that
I see yeah it's because you helped other
people see things okay
it doesn't have anything to do with
chemicals and shape of the cornea and
then rods and cones forget all that okay
you see because you have given sight to
others okay guys you have taken care of
other people's eyes okay
[Music]
mm okay I know I'm out of time Tim but
just remember what I'm taking it from
they're gonna kill me if I don't come
[Music]
I am the gajin Asst accountant comes
back Chapter three right the accountant
comes back yes I would like to make a
suggestion the eye is like a fire the
eye is like a fire fires only burn other
things fires don't burn fires if the
fire burned the fire then the fire will
go out right away because the fire would
burn the fire so in the gardener just
because something does something doesn't
mean has to do it for itself otherwise
fires would burn on fire and they would
disappear in one certain okay like that
all right
how does the guys gonna deal with that
I'm not gonna tell you all right but
you're so lucky
oh wait it's not ending this year
[Music]
yeah okay
I want your homework answer to talk
about walking going through the door I
want your homework answer to talk about
going to the door that's all you have a
clue okay the homework question is
what's the counter example that the
accountant gives it's fire tired to the
door okay in your answer tired to walk
into the door good luck I'm not helping
you
and that's all I gave you this me okay
don't forget your relapse okay let's go
choose a Singapore mr. Chao Chao Chi Chi
[Music]
some caching
see
[Music]
some machines also she said